<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.6.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2018-01-05T23:38:24+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">SPIN Mancheter</title><subtitle>Join SPIN and let's tackle the ongoing issue of homelessness and poverty in Manchester together.</subtitle><author><name>SPIN</name></author><entry><title type="html">Mark at the Be Proud Awards</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/mark-at-the-be-proud-awards/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Mark at the Be Proud Awards" /><published>2017-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-12-05T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/mark-at-the-be-proud-awards</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/mark-at-the-be-proud-awards/">&lt;p&gt;Manchester’s Be Proud Awards is an annual event hosted by Manchester City Council to provide an opportunity to celebrate all of the unsung heroes and volunteers of our beautiful city. We at SPIN are fortunate enough to be in the midst of a finalist for the much coveted Volunteer Of The Year Award.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/be-proud/mark-award-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-left&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Mark Evans, co-founder of SPIN, was nominated by A Connolly Ltd (based in Wigan) for his exceptional generosity, selflessness and motivation when it comes to helping the destitute and those in need. Not only has he established a street kitchen with his brother, John, that delivers restaurant quality food on a weekly basis but also co-created a sanctuary for those that need a roof over their head and to get off the streets in our emergency homeless shelter, The Well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Currently Mark has contributed to taking 20 people off the streets, finding permanent jobs for 7 homeless folks and helping to overcome substance abuse with weekly AA meetings held at The Well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to this, Mark volunteers a lot of his time delivering food parcels to people in Manchester which cannot afford to provide for themselves. His undiminishing drive to help those in need sees him helping collect food for FareShare - one of Manchester’s biggest food banks based in Smithfield Market.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/be-proud/john-and-mark-small.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-right&quot; class=&quot;align-right&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Dressed up to the nines, Mark, John (his brother and Co-Founder of SPIN), and Adele (nominator from A Connolly Ltd and volunteer at SPIN) attended the glittering gala dinner and awards ceremony in Manchester Town Hall’s Great Hall where they brushed shoulders with other finalists, nominators and sponsors. A well deserved change for a man that gives everything he can to help others; a man that expects nothing in return for his generosity; a humble man that just wants to do good for those without the opportunity to help themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Congratulations Mark on being recognised for all of your fantastic work. Here’s to another year of outstanding achievement with SPIN and The Well.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jamie Dennis</name></author><summary type="html">Marc, a volunteer of the year finalist at the Be Proud Awards in Manchester</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Jamie is shaving his head to raise money for SPIN</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/jamie-is-shaving-his-head-to-raise-funds/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Jamie is shaving his head to raise money for SPIN" /><published>2017-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</published><updated>2017-11-21T00:00:00+00:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/jamie-is-shaving-his-head-to-raise-funds</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/jamie-is-shaving-his-head-to-raise-funds/">&lt;h2 id=&quot;jamie-is-raising-funds-for-spin&quot;&gt;Jamie is raising funds for SPIN&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And this lion is doing so by shaving off his mane! Go to &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/gwdwg-supporting-people-in-need&quot;&gt;Jamie’s fundraising page&lt;/a&gt; to find out more. Here is Jamie’s message to all those willing to give to our cause:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Good day,&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am writing as a member of a not for profit, grass roots organisation striving to provide the most basic human rights to those on the streets and/or in need.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our organisation is called Supporting People In Need (SPIN). We began over two years ago when our founders Marc and John, two brother from Manchester, took it upon themselves to walk the streets of this beautiful city handing out sandwiches, hot drinks and clothing to the destitute. Due to an injury suffered whilst serving for our national armed forces, John was unable to continue to take to the streets and began plotting a stationary street kitchen with Marc. With a lot of hard graft the lads were able to make that dream come true and to this day &lt;strong&gt;upwards of 50 visitors come and indulge on a three course, restaurant standard of food&lt;/strong&gt; outside the Manchester Cathedral &lt;strong&gt;every Thursday night&lt;/strong&gt;. We provide a gorgeous variety of foods, hot/cold drinks and snacks as well as clothing, an ear to bend and a warm, caring connection from a genuine bunch of volunteers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In conjunction with this, a local parish saw the great work the boys were doing and wanted to help. The Coverdale Church on Coverdale Close, Ardwick was a dilapidated, rat infested building fit only for demolition until it was offered to SPIN. The Pastor always had the dream of creating a sanctuary for those without permanent housing to come worship, eat, relax and sleep as well as &lt;strong&gt;providing a stepping stone for those on the streets to progress back in to society&lt;/strong&gt;; either &lt;strong&gt;through overcoming substance abuse&lt;/strong&gt;, volunteering to actually &lt;strong&gt;finding jobs&lt;/strong&gt; and giving control back to the destitute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With a lot of hard work Marc, John and a whole host of generous volunteers helped to transform this battered building into The Well, a fully functioning church with an industrial kitchen, full sized canteen, games/entertainment room and 12 beds which are all currently occupied by those seeking refuge from the harsh streets of Manchester.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/images/jamie.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;image-left&quot; class=&quot;align-left&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At The Well, those who are offered sanctuary must volunteer some of their time to maintaining and managing the facilities. In addition to this, they spend time working for a local food charity called FareShare Greater Manchester which was launched in October 2008 to support communities to combat food poverty and food waste in and around Manchester. The guys who give time to FareShare receive food parcels in exchange for their time and as a thank you FareShare donate a very generous amount of food to The Well which is used to feed those staying, the surrounding community (Sunday roast dinner) and the food kitchen on a Thursday night. &lt;strong&gt;SPIN&lt;/strong&gt; has additionally been &lt;strong&gt;very successful in finding jobs for some&lt;/strong&gt; of the occupants of The Well including warehouse work, retail and catering works to name a few.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;There is currently no other self funded, not for profit charity doing as much as we are in Manchester&lt;/strong&gt;. Feeding, homing and finding jobs for the destitute. A lot of the funds have either come from the pockets of the patriots running the organisation or from donations as well as some money from the church funds itself. We have plans to expand the living quarters so we can house more seeking sanctuary but we are running low on funds. If you can help by donating whatever you can in order to make The Well a success then you’ll be helping those within the walls of the sanctuary but also hundreds, even thousands of people on the streets.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;go-to-jamies-gofundme-page&quot;&gt;Go to Jamie’s gofundme page&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Help us support the homeless by going to Jamie’s gofundme page:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center;&quot;&gt;
	&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.gofundme.com/gwdwg-supporting-people-in-need&quot; class=&quot;btn btn--primary btn--large&quot; onclick=&quot;ga('send', 'event', 'CTA', 'click', 'gofundme-Jamie');&quot;&gt;Donate to the fund&lt;/a&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big thanks from all of us here at SPIN.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name>Jamie Dennis</name></author><summary type="html">Jamie is raising money for SPIN... by shaving his head!</summary></entry></feed>